And the owner of Sabini fell in love
with the the Barbareska 1961 and he
bought 900 cases. 900 cases.
[Music]
Why spectator?
Roberta
[Music]
Angela.
Barbaresco.
Barbresco.
[Music]
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
[Music]
for
Brunello.
Earth.
Hi, Joani. Welcome to Taiwan. Hello.
Pleasure to be back. I think everybody's
so excited, especially the the wine
lovers and and the fans of Gaia and the
and the wine connoisseurs is so so
excited. I've heard uh over these past
weeks that when people know that you're
coming, they're so excited that the new
generation, the fifth generation of of
of Gaia is is actually uh emerging and
and especially coming to Taiwan to
promote the wine. So, as always, I think
you should let our fans and the the fans
of Gaia to kind of know a little bit
about Gaia, your family history, and
maybe some little stories that you
really cannot find on the internet.
Yeah. Yes. We are a family business.
Gaia was founded in 1859 from my great
greatgrandfather Joavanni Gaya. Okay. In
the family, creativity is not our
strongest fit. Oh, no. Because since
1859, all the generations have been
Joanni, Angelo. My grandfather was
Jovanni. My father is Angelo. I'm
Joavanni. So next generation is very
easy to guess. So there's two names. Two
names. So the winery was founded in
Barbaresco in Pigmont. So northwestern
part of Italy in this little tiny piece
of land called Lang where there are Baro
and Barbaresco which are two very small
towns that give the names to to the
wines and where the king varietal here
is Nebio. Uh the winery in 1859
initially was not actually founded as a
winery itself but it was founded as a
restaurant and Joanna the founder had a
small vineyard of nebula that he was
cultivating every year and then in the
years that he deemed to be the best
years ears he was actually bottling the
wine and then he was sending it into his
restaurant. So your great
great-grandfather actually is a
restaurant here. Yes. Started as a
restaurant. It was called in Italian we
say lost debap which means the steam
restaurant because below Barbaresco
there is a river flowing that is called
the tano river and in the 1850s there
was a a steamboat that was crossing from
side to side of the river. So the steam
restaurant because of so the restaurant
is actually located next to the river
close to the river. And actually it's in
the center of Barbares is where the
winery today is located. Okay. Because
then every generation dug a piece more
of the winery and expanded the the wine.
Okay. By the beginning of the 1900s,
most of the guests that were coming to
the restaurant were asking to buy wine
instead of eating in the restaurant.
Mhm. So we assume that the food was not
as good as wine. And so in 1912 he
closed the restaurant and started to
focus only in the production of of wine.
So that's how the history started. And
then after that it's been four uh
generation. The second generation was
the generation of Angelo Gaya and Clild
has been a fundamental woman in our
family. But I have to say in general
women have always had a very prominent
role not only in our family but in
pigment in general because they were the
ones that were controlling everything.
You mean the women? No, not only
everywhere the whole world making sure
that making sure that the husbands were
running
behaving. And uh today still like that
in in the family because I have my
mother plus my two sisters agana.
So the men in the family are completely
outnumbered.
No, that's the that's the truth. So
Clild for us was
an example. Uh she was the one that
started to give a different direction
into the winer. She was the one that
pushed her husband Angelo to increase
the quality of uh the wines. She had a
big influence on my father Angelo on my
grandfather Jovandi and because of this
she has been dedicated two wines. One is
Gay which is our Chardonnet that we
produce in Barbaresco where Guy is
actually dedicated to two women of the
family. One is Clild de Ray, my great
grandmother. And the other one is my
sister Ga that was born in 1979, which
was the first plantation of of the
vineyard of Charardon. Uh the second
wine is Tildina, which is one of the
three single vineyards that we produce
in Vervaresco. It's a wine that came out
in the 19 in 1970. H where Tild is a
nickname Grild T. Oh, so it's also your
great-grandmother's nickname. Yes,
whereas sorry is a is a word that comes
from the pigment is dialect and sorry in
pigment is they always indicate the most
prestigious pieces of land because they
are the ones that are always exposed
south. So the one that gets the highest
amount of uh of sun. So the vineyard is
facing south. South
the vineyard facing south. Yeah. Sorry.
Because sur
that in Italian means sun. Oh, but but
sur
it means sun. So it comes on the word
it's a derivative of sole but then in
pedigmont is it becomes sur. Okay. Uh
third generation was my grandfather
Javanni. My grandfather did a lot for
for the winery. He was first of all a a
believer, a true believer in Nebio
because he believed in Nebio and in the
Barbaresco
town in the Barbaresco region in the
Baromination in times where nobody even
knew of the existence of the Lang region
and where Nebola was not a variety that
was popular as it became today. So my
grandfather loved Barbaresco. The
borders of his world were the borders of
Barbaresco. If you were coming from the
opposite side of the Tanner or River
that flows just below Barbaresco, for
him you were a foreigner, not even
Italian or Pedmont. You were coming from
a different continent because his world
was the border of of Barbaresco. For 25
years, he has been the mayor of
Barbaresco, which I did not know that.
Puts it in perspective how much he loved
the area. So your grandfather is for 25
years of Barresco and uh he did a lot
for um not only for for the winery but I
think for for the region in general in
between the 1930s and the and the end of
the 1970s he managed to buy some of the
best vineyards located in Barbaresco and
he did that for almost 50 years without
really having competition from anyone.
Uh because at that time there was no
interest in buying land in Barbaresco.
The few people that wanted to create
something in the lang they were going to
Barolo because Baro in the past had a
bigger reputation compared to
Barbaresco. The Barbaresco for a long
time has been considered the steprother
of the of the Baro. The wine that was
less tanic, less edible, less
structured, less powerful, less in
general compared to the Barbaris. Today
things have changed because I think with
the climate change with warmer climatic
conditions it's almost like the
Barbaresco did a gym membership and put
up some of the muscles that were missing
in the past. So today there is a
difference in terms of style, not
anymore in terms of reputation, but it's
almost like tables have turned because
today is Barola that is trying to chase
the elegance and delicacy that usually
you find in um in the barbaris. So my my
my grandfather left us a big heritage
because the wines that we produce today,
the blend of our Barbaresco, the single
vineyards from Barbaresco were vineyard
that he purchased and that he left in
he was a he was a a visionary because in
in his vineyards he abolished
sharecropping. Okay. So, what is that?
So, sharecropping is a way of
cultivating land that to me it's
incredible that lasted for so long
because it's a medieval was in it was
created in the middle ages and it was
abolished in Italy with a government
decree in 1968. So, it lasted for almost
1,000 years. Basically, sharecropping
means that I'm the owner of the land and
uh if I have uh 10 different uh pieces
of land, I assign each one to a
different sharecropper to a different
farmer and the farmer cultivates that
land for the for one year and at the end
of the year the what is produced gets
divided. Partly go part goes to the
sharecropper, part goes to the land. But
the problem of sharecropping is that
it's not a way to produce quality
because the sharecropper is not awarded
in producing quality because is is
awarded only in quantity. So the more he
produces the more he gets back at the
end of the year. So in 1948, my
grandfather shifted all of his
sharecroers into monthly paid employees.
And this was a benefit for them because
they were receiving a a salary and and
their salary was not depending on how
the year went. But most of all, it was a
benefit for my grandfather because he
could decide how he wanted to um to work
in his own vineyards to really be able
to uh create the quality that he wanted.
In the 1960s, he started a philosophy
that we still use today. That is the
philosophy of not bottling all the
vintages. Not all of our wines came out
every year, but they come out only when
we think that they can be the best
vintages. And we still do it today
because our single vineyards, the
pinnacle of our production, they only
come out when they can be the best
expression, not only of the variety, but
also of the vintage. Doing it today
still is a big sacrifice. Yeah. Because
I know that your single vineyard is not
produced every year. Yeah. Exactly. So
it's a big sacrifice. But imagine doing
this 60 years ago when nobody understood
or even knew nebio when you couldn't
give commercial visibility to to the
wines and most of all where you had a
climate that was different because it
was a colder climate. It was difficult
for Nebio to always reach not even
perfect just decent maturation. So there
were times in which my grandfather was
keeping two or three vintages in a row
of his Barbaresco. But he did that to
make sure that quality was always
a guarantee. Uh and we kept this also we
kept we kept this philosophy also today.
My grandfather gave us a lot of um
teachings. He's the one also that
started to give a visibility to the Gaia
wines to the Gaia brand in the Italian
market because in the 1960s he's the one
also that started to work with the
restaurants for us restaurants are
fundamental 70% of our wines today are
sold in restaurants because it's a way
for us to always give a visibility to to
the wines to increase the also the
reputation of of the wines. So in the
1960s when uh he started to focus in
restaurants in Italy, he didn't have a
lot of clients but had few but very good
clients. In 1964 he released his 1961
Barbaresco and he was a very good friend
with the owner of a restaurant called
the Savini restaurant which still is
present in Milan. is in the galleria duo
in Milan, a very historic restaurant and
the owner of Sabini fell in love with
the the Barbar 1961 and he bought 900
cases. 900 and he put it in his in his
restaurant. So that was important to
give visibility to place the wines in
the right places and so that started to
give visibility and reputation to the
Gaia wines in the Italian market. It was
my father that started to give
visibility in the foreign market because
my my father Angelo started to work into
the winery in 1961. For seven years he
uh worked in the vineyards and then he
started to get more involved also in the
wine making of the wines. And then in
uh he started well was beginning of the
1970s started to travel
outside of Italy explaining the uh the
nebula variety and giving
the the history of this uh variety and
he started initially with the three
markets uh Switzerland, Germany and the
US. Then uh today today we export in
more than 100 different countries. So
it's been a a gradual uh uh development.
My father has always been a a different
thinker. If all the producers go in this
direction, he goes in the opposite uh
direction because he finds value in
doing things in a different way. He was
the first one who introduced
international varieties in
the Lang region. in in the 1960s when he
came into the winery he revolutionized
the pruning on Nebio to focus on less
production but to make sure that more
quality also was always ensured. He is
the one that expanded also the horizons
of GA because in
1994 he bought an already existing
winery in Montelino called Panta. In
1996 he created the Kamaranda located in
the Bulgaria on the Taskan coast. In
2017 we started our latest project in
Sicily called IDA on Mount Ena. And then
actually in 2015 we developed a new
project in Pigmont located just 20
minutes away from Barbaresco but uh 400
m higher in Al. The area is called
Alanga. So so 400 it's pretty high. It's
620 650 m of altitude. 650 mit. The the
the name of the town where we where we
bought the land is called Totinella.
Okay. Which is part of the Altalanga
region, which Ala in Italian means high
because Altalanga starts at 500 m and
grows all the way up to 900 m of
altitude. It develops south of Bar and
Barbaresco all the way down to the
border with the Gurya. And there we
bought 30 acres of land which were
covered with the hazelnuts. We took out
the hazelnuts and then in 2018 we
started planting and most of what we
planted is charardon and sin blanc
because we already have experience with
these varieties. But then we also did
some experimental varieties. So we
planted we have rising pinocoas
some local
we created a brand new winery that is
our new whites uh winery because our
pedigmont is white. So Rosibas at Brasa
and Gu in terms of bification have been
moved into this new property. So in
Barbaresco only reds focusing on the in
this new property in Totela only whites.
So we can give even further. So so so
the alini brasa vista is open. No no no
is coming. So, Rosibas bras and
and the idea in the future is to merge
together the production that we have in
the lang region of our of Char and
Blanca where we are a lower elevation a
little bit warmer climate where we can
get more structure and roundness with
the production in at higher elevation
where we get more verticality more
freshness and more facility. Well, when
you were saying that your your you were
joking that your family is not so
interesting and innovative, I don't
agree with it because actually it you
your your family is very very
innovative. Okay. So so one of the thing
is um I think your your your father was
also one of the pioneer in terms of the
international burger idol and one of
them was Cabernet Soyong. It's a very
premium Cabernet Soyong and he named it
Don Maji. Why?
[Music]